Guide to the National Education Association-Committees records, 1857-1996 NEA1003.RG
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Joint Committee of the NEA and Magazine Publishers Association, 1958-1972; Series 16; 0.75 Linear Feet
  - The American High School Graduate: Report of a Conference Held April 25, 1962, series 16 (Box 4321, Folder 2)
  - American Textbook Publishers Institute-Annual Report, 1963-1964; Series 16 (Box 1276, Folder 1)
  - America's Stake in a Literature Society: Highlights of the Discussions Third National Conference of Magazine Editors and Educators, February 1956; series 16 (Box 4321, Folder 3)
  - Controversial Issues in the Classroom, 1961; series 16 (Box 4321, Folder 4)
  - "The Dimensions of Intelligence and Creativity", 1963; Series 16 (Box 1276, Folder 2)
  - Editors at WOrk: Report of the 1961 NEA-MPA Editorial Internship Project, 1962; series 16 (Box 4321, Folder 5)
  - History, 1966; Series 16 (Box 1276, Folder 3)
  - "The Interest of Publishers of Educational Material in Copyright Law Revision", August 1963; Series 16 (Box 1276, Folder 4)
  - Joint Committee of the NEA and American Textbook Publishers Institute, August 1965; Series 16 (Box 1276, Folder 5)
  - Keeping Pace with Knowledge: A conference of Magazine Editors and Educators, June 1954; series 16 (Box 4321, Folder 6)
  - "Magazines in the Classroom", 1960; Series 16 (Box 1276, Folder 6)
  - Magazines in the Classroom, March 1960; series 16 (Box 4321, Folder 7)
  - [NEA - Magazine Publishers Association] [Photographs], 1956-1958; Series 16 (Box 3517, Folder 7)
    Conant, James B.; Corey, Arthur Fisher
  - "New Models in American Education", December 1963; Series 16 (Box 1276, Folder 7)
  - Papers, 1958-1965; Series 16 (Box 1276, Folder 8)
  - Photos, circa 1965; Series 16 (Box 1276, Folder 9)
  - Perspectives: First Step Toward the Great Society, 1965; Series 16 (Box 4421, Folder 1)
  - Proceedings of the Editor and Educator Conference: The Purpose of Education in the American Democracy, November 1958; series 16 (Box 4321, Folder 8)
  - Project, circa 1965; Series 16 (Box 1276, Folder 10)
  - Reader's Digest Newsweek Saturday Review: Report of the 1963 Editorial Internship Project, 1964; series 16 (Box 4321, Folder 9)
  - Science and American Education, February 1958; series 16 (Box 4321, Folder 10)
  - "Selecting Instructional Materials for Purchase", 1972; Series 16 (Box 1276, Folder 11)
  - "Tomorrow in Education, National Magazines Report on America's Schools", 1966; Series 16 (Box 1276, Folder 12)
  - "Tomorrow in Education, National Magazines Report on America's Schools", 1966; Series 16 (Box 4421, Folder 2)
  - Toward a Better Informed America: Second Conference of Magazine Editors and Educators, May 1955; series 16 (Box 4321, Folder 11)
  - What is Wrong with the Teaching Profession - A Second Look, April 1958; series 16 (Box 4321, Folder 12)
  - "Who Controls American Education?", 1967; Series 16 (Box 1276, Folder 13)
- Joint Committee of the NEA and National Congress of Parents and Teachers, 1906-1968; Series 17; 0.25 Linear Feet
  The Joint Committee of the NEA and the National Congress of Parents and Teachers was established in 1929. The Committee was composed of five members from each organization and its chairmanship alternated annually.
  The Committee was created to discuss programs and objectives to improve public education, to provide dialogue and interchange, and to coordinate activities for which mutual support can be established and achieved.
  Series contains publications created by the Joint Committee of the NEA and National Congress of Parents and Teachers.
  - "Danger from the Far Right", circa 1966; Series 17 (Box 1276, Folder 14)
  - "Grievances!-The Parents Speak, The Teachers Speak", circa 1964; Series 17 (Box 1276, Folder 15)
  - "Growing Up in Modern America", 1968; Series 17 (Box 1276, Folder 16)
  - "How to Get the Most Out of School", 1968; Series 17 (Box 1276, Folder 17)
  - "How to Use the Congress Publications", 1932; Series 17 (Box 1276, Folder 18)
  - "National Congress of Mothers Magazine", November 1906; Series 17 (Box 1276, Folder 19)
  - Order Form, circa 1906; Series 17 (Box 1276, Folder 20)
  - "Our Public Schools", 1934; Series 17 (Box 1276, Folder 21)
  - "Proposals on Education Legislation", circa 1968; Series 17 (Box 1276, Folder 22)
  - "Teachers and Parents Together for Kids", circa 1951; Series 17 (Box 1276, Folder 23)
- Joint Committee of the NEA and National School Board Association, 1951-1973; Series 18; 1.5 Linear Feet
  The Joint Committee of the NEA and the National School Boards Association was established in 1956. The Committee was composed of five members from each organization and the Presidents serve as cochairmen for one year.
  The Committee was created to discuss programs and objectives to improve public education, to provide dialog and interchange, and to coordinate activities for which mutual support can be established and achieved. The committee was dissolved in 1972.
  Series contains materials created within the Joint Committee of the NEA and National School Board Association. The files include meeting notes, papers, a large reference manual on school board policies, and materials related to the Teaching about Public Schools project.
  - Ad Hoc Committee, 1951-1966; Series 18 (Box 1277, Folder 1)
  - Delegate Handbook for Delegate Assembly Workshop, April 1972; Series 18 (Box 1277, Folder 2)
  - General, 1963-1971; Series 18 (Box 1277, Folder 3)
  - How to Develop Written Policies [1/2], 1960; Series 18 (Box 4703, Folder 1)
  - How to Develop Written Policies [2/2], 1960; Series 18 (Box 4703, Folder 2)
  - Meeting, January 1969; Series 18 (Box 1277, Folder 4)
  - Meeting, January 1970; Series 18 (Box 1277, Folder 5)
  - Meeting, September 1970; Series 18 (Box 1277, Folder 6)
  - Meeting, January 1971; Series 18 (Box 1277, Folder 7)
  - Meeting, September 1971; Series 18 (Box 1278, Folder 1)
  - Meeting, January 1972; Series 18 (Box 1278, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, April 1957-January 1972; Series 18 (Box 1278, Folder 3)
  - Mobile, Alabama, 1971; Series 18 (Box 1278, Folder 4)
  - NEA-NSBA Members, 1971-1973; Series 18 (Box 1278, Folder 5)
  - NSBA Washington DC Office, 1967-1969; Series 18 (Box 1278, Folder 6)
  - Papers, March 1966-July 1972; Series 18 (Box 1278, Folder 7)
    Contains 15 photos and 53 negatives.
  - Papers, December 1971-July 1972; Series 18 (Box 1278, Folder 8)
  - Reference Manual on Written School Board Policies [file 1/3], 1961; Series 18 (Box 1278, Folder 9)
  - Reference Manual on Written School Board Policies [file 2/3], 1961; Series 18 (Box 1278, Folder 10)
  - Reference Manual on Written School Board Policies [file 3/3], 1961; Series 18 (Box 1279, Folder 1)
  - "Reference Manual on Written School Board Policies", 1962; Series 18 (Box 1279, Folder 2)
  - School Board Member Qualifications, 1969; Series 18 (Box 1279, Folder 3)
  - Southern Regional School Boards Conference, 1971; Series 18 (Box 1279, Folder 4)
  - State School Boards Meetings, August 1970-November 1971; Series 18 (Box 1279, Folder 5)
  - State School Boards Meetings, 1971-1972; Series 18 (Box 1279, Folder 6)
  - Teaching about the Public Schools Project [file 1/3], 1966-1972; Series 18 (Box 1279, Folder 7)
  - Teaching about the Public Schools Project [file 2/3], 1966-1972; Series 18 (Box 1279, Folder 8)
  - Teaching about the Public Schools Project [file 3/3], 1966-1972; Series 18 (Box 1279, Folder 9)
  - Written School Board Policies, 1966-1969; Series 18 (Box 1279, Folder 10)
- Legislation Committee, 1945-1987; Series 19; 10.5 Linear Feet
  Series contains materials created within the Legislation Committee. The files include agenda books, conference materials, minutes of meetings, publications and recommendations and objectives.
  The Legislation Committee serves as the federal legislative agency and clearinghouse for the NEA. The committee formulates and recommends federal legislative policy for consideration, interprets application of adopted federal policy, formulates and evaluates action policies, and serves as the clearinghouse for all federal legislative objectives and programs of the NEA.
  The Legislative Commission began in 1935, focusing on the fight for general federal aid legislation and records one of its first victories as the repeal of the "little red rider" to the 1935 DC salary appropriation bill. In 1972, the Legislative Committee was established to absorb the functions of the Legislative Commission and the Citizenship Committee under one body.
  - Agenda Book, May 1969; Series 19 (Box 1280, Folder 1)
  - Agenda Book, May 1969; Series 19 (Box 1280, Folder 2)
  - Agenda Book, July 1969; Series 19 (Box 1280, Folder 3)
  - Agenda Book, October 1969; Series 19 (Box 1280, Folder 4)
  - Agenda Book, January 1970; Series 19 (Box 1280, Folder 5)
  - Agenda Book, April 1970; Series 19 (Box 1280, Folder 6)
  - Agenda Book, June 1970; Series 19 (Box 1280, Folder 7)
  - Agenda Book, October 1970; Series 19 (Box 1280, Folder 8)
  - Agenda Book, December 1970; Series 19 (Box 1281, Folder 1)
  - Agenda Book, February 1971; Series 19 (Box 1281, Folder 2)
  - Agenda Book, March 1971; Series 19 (Box 1281, Folder 3)
  - Agenda Book, April 1971; Series 19 (Box 1281, Folder 4)
  - Agenda Book, April 1971-May 1971; Series 19 (Box 1281, Folder 5)
  - Agenda Book, June 1971; Series 19 (Box 1282, Folder 1)
  - Agenda Book, June 1971; Series 19 (Box 1282, Folder 2)
  - Agenda Book, September 1971; Series 19 (Box 1282, Folder 3)
  - Agenda Book, November 1971; Series 19 (Box 1282, Folder 4)
  - Agenda Book, November 1971; Series 19 (Box 1282, Folder 5)
  - Agenda Book, January 1972; Series 19 (Box 1282, Folder 6)
  - Agenda Book, January 1972; Series 19 (Box 1282, Folder 7)
  - Agenda Book, March 1972; Series 19 (Box 1282, Folder 8)
  - Agenda Book, March 1972; Series 19 (Box 1283, Folder 1)
  - Agenda Book, April 1972; Series 19 (Box 1283, Folder 2)
  - Agenda Book, April 1972; Series 19 (Box 1283, Folder 3)
  - Agenda Book, May 1972; Series 19 (Box 1283, Folder 4)
  - Agenda Book, May 1972; Series 19 (Box 1283, Folder 5)
  - Agenda Book, June 1972; Series 19 (Box 1283, Folder 6)
  - Agenda Book, June 1972; Series 19 (Box 1283, Folder 7)
  - Agenda Book, September 1972; Series 19 (Box 1283, Folder 8)
  - Agenda Book, September 1972; Series 19 (Box 1283, Folder 9)
  - Agenda Book, January 1973; Series 19 (Box 1283, Folder 10)
  - Agenda Book, January 1973; Series 19 (Box 1283, Folder 11)
  - Agenda Book, March 1973; Series 19 (Box 1283, Folder 12)
  - Agenda Book, March 1973; Series 19 (Box 1284, Folder 1)
  - Agenda Book, April 1973; Series 19 (Box 1284, Folder 2)
  - Agenda Book, April 1973; Series 19 (Box 1284, Folder 3)
  - Agenda Book, June 1973; Series 19 (Box 1284, Folder 4)
  - Agenda Book, October 1973; Series 19 (Box 1284, Folder 5)
  - Agenda Book, December 1973; Series 19 (Box 1284, Folder 6)
  - Agenda Book, January 1974; Series 19 (Box 1284, Folder 7)
  - Agenda Book, February 1974; Series 19 (Box 1284, Folder 8)
  - Agenda Book, March 1974; Series 19 (Box 1284, Folder 9)
  - Agenda Book, May 1974; Series 19 (Box 1285, Folder 1)
  - Agenda Book, September 1974; Series 19 (Box 1285, Folder 2)
  - Agenda Book, December 1974; Series 19 (Box 1285, Folder 3)
  - Agenda Book, January 1975; Series 19 (Box 1285, Folder 4)
  - Agenda Book, February 1975; Series 19 (Box 1285, Folder 5)
  - Agenda Book, April 1975; Series 19 (Box 1285, Folder 6)
  - Agenda Book, May 1975; Series 19 (Box 1285, Folder 7)
  - Agenda Book, May 1975; Series 19 (Box 1285, Folder 8)
  - Agenda Book, November 1975; Series 19 (Box 1285, Folder 9)
  - Agenda Book, January 1976; Series 19 (Box 1285, Folder 10)
  - Agenda Book, March 1976; Series 19 (Box 1285, Folder 11)
  - Agenda Book, March 1976; Series 19 (Box 1286, Folder 1)
  - Agenda Book, April 1976; Series 19 (Box 1286, Folder 2)
  - Agenda Book, July 1976; Series 19 (Box 1286, Folder 3)
  - Agenda Book, September 1976; Series 19 (Box 1286, Folder 4)
  - Agenda Book, November 1976; Series 19 (Box 1286, Folder 5)
  - Agenda Book, December 1976; Series 19 (Box 1286, Folder 6)
  - Agenda Book, January 1977; Series 19 (Box 1286, Folder 7)
  - Agenda Book, March 1977; Series 19 (Box 1286, Folder 8)
  - Agenda Book, March 1977; Series 19 (Box 1286, Folder 9)
  - Agenda Book, April 1977; Series 19 (Box 1287, Folder 1)
  - Agenda Book, December 1977; Series 19 (Box 1287, Folder 2)
  - Agenda Book, January 1978; Series 19 (Box 1287, Folder 3)
  - Agenda Book [file 1/2], March 1978; Series 19 (Box 1287, Folder 4)
  - Agenda Book [file 2/2], March 1978; Series 19 (Box 1287, Folder 5)
  - Agenda Book, April 1978; Series 19 (Box 1287, Folder 6)
  - Agenda Book, October 1978; Series 19 (Box 1287, Folder 7)
  - Agenda Book, January 1979; Series 19 (Box 1288, Folder 1)
  - Agenda Book, February 1979; Series 19 (Box 1288, Folder 2)
  - Agenda Book, March 1979-April 1979; Series 19 (Box 1288, Folder 3)
    Contains 1 button.
  - Agenda Book, October 1979; Series 19 (Box 1288, Folder 4)
  - Agenda Book, December 1979; Series 19 (Box 1288, Folder 5)
  - Agenda Book, January 1980; Series 19 (Box 1288, Folder 6)
  - Agenda Book [file 1/2], March 1980; Series 19 (Box 1288, Folder 7)
  - Agenda Book [file 2/2], March 1980; Series 19 (Box 1289, Folder 1)
  - Agenda Book, October 1980; Series 19 (Box 1289, Folder 2)
  - Agenda Book, January 1981; Series 19 (Box 1289, Folder 3)
  - Agenda Book [file 1/2], February 1981-March 1981; Series 19 (Box 1289, Folder 4)
  - Agenda Book [file 2/2], February 1981-March 1981; Series 19 (Box 1289, Folder 5)
  - Agenda Book, March 1981; Series 19 (Box 1289, Folder 6)
  - Agenda Book, March 1981; Series 19 (Box 1289, Folder 7)
  - Agenda Book, November 1981; Series 19 (Box 1290, Folder 1)
  - Agenda Book, November 1981; Series 19 (Box 1290, Folder 2)
  - Agenda Book [file 1/2], February 1982; Series 19 (Box 1290, Folder 3)
  - Agenda Book [file 2/2], February 1982; Series 19 (Box 1290, Folder 4)
  - Agenda Book, February 1982; Series 19 (Box 1290, Folder 5)
  - Agenda Book, March 1982; Series 19 (Box 1290, Folder 6)
  - Agenda Book [file 1/2], March 1982; Series 19 (Box 1290, Folder 7)
  - Agenda Book [file 2/2], March 1982; Series 19 (Box 1290, Folder 8)
  - Agenda Book, October 1982; Series 19 (Box 1306, Folder 1)
  - Agenda Book [file 1/2], February 1983; Series 19 (Box 1306, Folder 2)
  - Agenda Book [file 2/2], February 1983; Series 19 (Box 1306, Folder 3)
  - Agenda Book, March 1983; Series 19 (Box 1306, Folder 4)
  - Agenda Book, October 1983; Series 19 (Box 1306, Folder 5)
  - Agenda Book, February 1984; Series 19 (Box 1316, Folder 1)
  - Agenda Book [file 1/2], March 1984; Series 19 (Box 1316, Folder 2)
  - Agenda Book [file 2/2], March 1984; Series 19 (Box 1316, Folder 3)
  - Agenda Book, November 1984; Series 19 (Box 1316, Folder 4)
  - Agenda Book, February 1985; Series 19 (Box 1316, Folder 5)
  - Agenda Book, March 1985; Series 19 (Box 1317, Folder 1)
  - Agenda Book, November 1985; Series 19 (Box 1317, Folder 2)
  - Agenda Book [file 1/2], February 1986; Series 19 (Box 1317, Folder 3)
  - Agenda Book [file 2/2], February 1986; Series 19 (Box 1317, Folder 4)
  - Agenda Book, March 1986; Series 19 (Box 1317, Folder 5)
  - Agenda Book, November 1986; Series 19 (Box 1318, Folder 1)
  - Agenda Book, February 1987; Series 19 (Box 1318, Folder 2)
  - American Educational Research Association Washington, D.C. Report For the Period From January 1, 1939 To February 1939 29, 1940, January 1939 - February 1940; Series 19 (Box 4911, Folder 3)
  - Conference [file 1/3], March 1980; Series 19 (Box 1318, Folder 3)
  - Conference [file 2/3], March 1980; Series 19 (Box 1318, Folder 4)
  - Conference [file 3/3], March 1980; Series 19 (Box 1318, Folder 5)
  - Conference, November 1980; Series 19 (Box 1319, Folder 1)
  - Conference, March 1981-December 1981; Series 19 (Box 1319, Folder 2)
  - Conference, October 1982-November 1982; Series 19 (Box 1319, Folder 3)
  - Conference, November 1982; Series 19 (Box 1319, Folder 4)
  - Conference-Background, October 1981-November 1981; Series 19 (Box 1319, Folder 5)
  - Conference-Correspondence, August 1981-December 1981; Series 19 (Box 1319, Folder 6)
  - Conference-Costs, November 1981-December 1981; Series 19 (Box 1319, Folder 7)
  - Conference-Evaluations, November 1982-December 1982; Series 19 (Box 1319, Folder 8)
  - Conference-Facilitator Packet, July 1981-November 1981; Series 19 (Box 1320, Folder 1)
  - Conference-Final Report, 1981; Series 19 (Box 1320, Folder 2)
  - Conference-Followup, November 1982-January 1983; Series 19 (Box 1320, Folder 3)
  - Conference-Invitations/Attendance, 1982; Series 19 (Box 1320, Folder 4)
  - Conference-Last Minute, November 1981; Series 19 (Box 1320, Folder 5)
  - Conference-Last Minute, November 1982; Series 19 (Box 1320, Folder 6)
  - Conference-Logistics, 1982; Series 19 (Box 1320, Folder 7)
  - Conference-Materials, November 1981; Series 19 (Box 1320, Folder 8)
  - Conference-Materials, November 1982; Series 19 (Box 1320, Folder 9)
  - Conference-Originals, 1982; Series 19 (Box 1321, Folder 1)
  - Conference-Participants, November 1981; Series 19 (Box 1321, Folder 2)
  - Convention Plans, 1972; Series 19 (Box 1321, Folder 3)
  - Education Department Plans [file 1/2], October 1979-December 1979; Series 19 (Box 1321, Folder 4)
  - Education Department Plans [file 2/2], October 1979-December 1979; Series 19 (Box 1321, Folder 5)
  - "Educational Needs for Fiscal Year 1980, Recommendations to the 96th Congress", Series 19 (Box 1321, Folder 6)
  - "For Civic Competence...", 1963; Series 19 (Box 1321, Folder 7)
  - General, 1952-1957; Series 19 (Box 1321, Folder 8)
  - "A Glossary of Legislative Terms", 1978; Series 19 (Box 1321, Folder 9)
  - History of, circa 1950; Series 19 (Box 1321, Folder 10)
  - Information File on Judiciary Committee, April- August 1971; series 19 (Box 4297, Folder 22)
  - Membership, 1962; Series 19 (Box 1321, Folder 11)
  - Meetings, August 1964-July 1965; Series 19 (Box 1321, Folder 12)
  - Meetings, August 1965-July 1966; Series 19 (Box 1322, Folder 1)
  - Meetings, August 1966-July 1967; Series 19 (Box 1322, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, September 1945-October 1949; Series 19 (Box 1322, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, January 1950-May 1953; Series 19 (Box 1322, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, June 1953-April 1956; Series 19 (Box 1322, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, June 1956-February 1960; Series 19 (Box 1322, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, June 1960-July 1962; Series 19 (Box 1323, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, August 1962-July 1963; Series 19 (Box 1323, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, August 1963-July 1964; Series 19 (Box 1323, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, August 1967-July 1969; Series 19 (Box 1323, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, September 1969-July 1971; Series 19 (Box 1323, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, September 1971-June 1972; Series 19 (Box 1324, Folder 1)
  - Recommendations, Papers, Objectives [file 1/2], May 1962-September 1962; Series 19 (Box 1324, Folder 2)
  - Recommendations, Papers, Objectives [file 2/2], May 1962-September 1962; Series 19 (Box 1324, Folder 3)
  - "The Reign of ETS, the Corporation that Makes Up Minds", January 1980; Series 19 (Box 1324, Folder 4)
  - "Report of the NCSEA Political Delivery System Committee", June 1976; Series 19 (Box 1324, Folder 5)
  - Reports, 1957-1967; Series 19 (Box 1324, Folder 6)
  - "School Energy Crisis: Problems and Solutions", 1977; Series 19 (Box 1324, Folder 7)
  - "Statement of the NEA on the Proposed Youth Employment Program before the Subcommittee on Elementary, Secondary, and Vocational Education of the House Committee on Education and Labor", February 1980; Series 19 (Box 1324, Folder 8)
  - Supplementary Report of the 1999 - 2000 Resolutions Committee, 2000-07-03-2000-07-06 (Box 4880, Folder 3)
  - White House Rally-Backup and History, April 1972-June 1972; Series 19 (Box 1324, Folder 9)
  - White House Rally-Money, 1972; Series 19 (Box 1324, Folder 10)
- Resolutions Committee, 1857-1987; Series 20; 2.5 Linear Feet
  The Resolutions Committee was formed to assist the activities of the Annual Convention of the NEA. The Resolutions Committee served to prepare recommendations for the Representative Assembly on general policies of the NEA Platform and Resolutions.
  Series contains materials created within the Resolutions Committee. The files include lists of members, meeting agendas, reports, publications, and lists of resolutions.
  The resolutions files are the highlight of these records and include the wording, dates and notes on approvals of numerous resolutions managed by the committee.
  - Correspondence, September 1985-April 1986; Series 20 (Box 1325, Folder 1)
  - Editing Committee, 1967-1970; Series 20 (Box 1325, Folder 2)
  - Functions and Purpose, 1985; Series 20 (Box 1325, Folder 3)
  - Implementation of Committee Report, April 1986-December 1987; Series 20 (Box 1325, Folder 4)
  - Items Approved by Resolutions Committee, March 1980; series 20 (Box 4494, Folder 10)
  - "Materials on Platform and Resolutions", April 1968; Series 20 (Box 1325, Folder 5)
  - Materials on Platform and Resolutions compiled for the NEA Resolutions Committee, March 31, 1965; Series 20 (Box 4008, Folder 15)
  - Meeting Agenda, February 1986; Series 20 (Box 1325, Folder 6)
  - Meeting Agenda, December 1986; Series 20 (Box 1325, Folder 7)
  - Members, 1984-1985; Series 20 (Box 1325, Folder 8)
  - Members, 1973-1980; Series 20 (Box 1325, Folder 9)
  - Members, 1972-1973; Series 20 (Box 1325, Folder 10)
  - Members [file 1/2], 1971-1972; Series 20 (Box 1326, Folder 1)
  - Members [file 2/2], 1971-1972; Series 20 (Box 1326, Folder 2)
  - Members and Alternates, 1962-1985; Series 20 (Box 1326, Folder 3)
    Contains 2 photos and 22 negatives.
  - Memorandum [School Utilization of Instructional Television Survey], March 6 1980; series 20 (Box 4494, Folder 11)
  - Minutes, Reports, 1977-1978; Series 20 (Box 1326, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous, 1986; Series 20 (Box 1326, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous, Drafts, Ware's Notes, 1977-1978; Series 20; Ware, Martha L. (Box 1327, Folder 1)
  - Pamphlets-Preliminary Report, 2001; NEA1003.RG (Box 2809, Folder 4)
  - Platform, 1863-1920; Series 20 (Box 1327, Folder 2)
  - Pre-Convention Report on Platform and Resolutions, June 1965; Series 20 (Box 1327, Folder 3)
  - Pre-Convention Report on Platform and Resolutions, June 1968; Series 20 (Box 1327, Folder 4)
  - "Preliminary Report of Editing Committee", May 1968; Series 20 (Box 1327, Folder 5)
  - Proposed Amendments to Bylaws and Rules, circa 1960; Series 20 (Box 1327, Folder 6)
  - Proposed Revision of Platform and Resolutions of the NEA, January 1969; Series 20 (Box 1327, Folder 7)
  - Rationale Concerning Conversion to the Metric System, May 1980 - June 1980; series 20 (Box 4494, Folder 12)
  - "Reorganization of the NEA", 1920; Series 20 (Box 1327, Folder 8)
  - Report, circa 1933; Series 20 (Box 1327, Folder 9)
  - Report, circa 1986; Series 20 (Box 1327, Folder 10)
  - Report, March 1986; Series 20 (Box 1327, Folder 11)
  - Report on Implementation of Resolutions and New Business Items, 1976; Series 20 (Box 1327, Folder 12)
  - Reports of the Committee on Resolutions, 1894-1939; Series 20 (Box 1327, Folder 13)
    Immediate Source of Acquisition note
    Gift [Acc #2009.048]
  - Resolutions, 1857-1938; Series 20 (Box 1328, Folder 1)
  - Resolutions, 1857-1935; Series 20 (Box 1328, Folder 2)
  - Resolutions, 1970-1971; Series 20 (Box 1328, Folder 3)
  - Resolutions (By Subject), 1921-1930; Series 20 (Box 1328, Folder 4)
  - Resolutions (By Subject), 1931-1950; Series 20 (Box 1328, Folder 5)
  - Resolutions (By Subject) [file 1/3], 1971; Series 20 (Box 1328, Folder 6)
  - Resolutions (By Subject) [file 2/3], 1971; Series 20 (Box 1329, Folder 1)
  - Resolutions (By Subject) [file 3/3], 1971; Series 20 (Box 1329, Folder 2)